Guide to the Donald Graham papers, 1960-1994.
Graham, Donald papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Donald Graham papers, 1960-1994.
21-26-3889
Donald Clyde Washington, Graham 1932.
5 cubic feet.
Correspondence, Manuscripts, Publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes correspondence, course material, meeting minutes, and subject files.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor emeritus of food science, Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes correspondence, course material, meeting minutes, and subject files.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Graham, Donald Clyde Washington,1932.; Cornell University--Faculty.; New York State College of Agriculture.Dept. of Food Science.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Collection is closed for processing.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Course Material
Series II. Talks and Conferences
Series III. Research and Professional
Series IV. Publications
Series V. Committees
Series VI. Organizations
Series VII. Correspondence
Series VIII. Biographical
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Course Material
  - Food Science (F. S.) 101 - Lecture on Genetic Engineering, Fall 1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - F. S. 607 - Advanced Food Microbiology, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - F. S. 411 - Food Mycology, 1984-1992 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - F. S. 411 - Lecture 1, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - F. S. - Lectures 2 and 3 - General Characteristics of Fungi, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - F. S. 411 - Lecture 4 - Detection, Isolation, and Identification of Fungi, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - F. S. 411 - Lecture - Water Activity, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - F. S. 411 - Mushrooms - Slides and Notes, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - F. S. 411 - Lecture 7 - Zygomycetes, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - F. S. 411 - Lecture - Ascomycetes, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - F. S. 411 - Lecture 8 - Yeasts, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - F. S. 411 - Lecture Materials, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - F. S. - Lab 1, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - F. S. 411 - Exam III, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - F. S. 411 - General (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - F. S. 411 - Lecture and Other Materials (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - F. S. 394 - Handouts, Fall 1988 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - F. S. 394 - Handouts, Fall 1990 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - F. S. 394 - Handouts, Fall 1992 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - F. S. 394 - Handouts, Fall 1993 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - F. S. 394 - Lecture 1 - Introduction, Fall 1993 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - F. S. 394 - Lecture 4 - Inhibitory Substances and Temperature, Fall 1992 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - F. S. 394 - Lecture 2 - pH, Fall 1993 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - F. S. 394 - Lecture 3 - Moisture Content/Water Activity: Oxidation-Reduction Potential and Inhibition Substances, Fall 1993 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - F. S. 394 - Lectures 7 and 8 - Common Methods for Estimating Microorganisms in Foods, Fall 1993 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - F. S. 394 - Lecture 10 - Pseudomonadaceae and Endobacteriaceae, Fall 1993 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - F. S. 394 - Lecture 11, Fall 1993 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - F. S. 394 - Lecture 12, Fall 1993 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - F. S. 394 - Lecture 13 - Bacillus/Clostridium, Fall 1993 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - F. S. 394 - Lecture 14 - Fungi in Foods, Fall 1993 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - F. S. 394 - Lecture 15 - Yeasts, Fall 1993 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - F. S. 411 - Syllabus, Fall 1992 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - F. S. 394 - Lectures (1), Spring 1986 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - F. S. 394 - Lectures (2), Spring 1986 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - F. S. 394 - Lecture 1, Fall 1987 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - F. S. 394 - Materials, Spring 1986 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Industrial Applications of Fungi (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - F. S. 497 - Lecture 7 - The Nature and Importance of Foods from the Sea, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - F. S. 497 - Lectures 23 and 24 - Sub-Saharan Africa (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - F. S. 497 - Lectures 22 and 23 - India (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - F. S. 497 - Lectures 20 and 21 - China (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - F. S. 394 - Lectures 16 and 17 - Microbiology of Food Fermentations (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Mycology Lecture, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Fungi - U. of Minnesota Short Course, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Newer Methods Lecture (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Cassava Course and Lecture, Spring 1981 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Food Microbiology Lecture Notes - Frank Busta, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Food Microbiology Lecture Notes - L. McKay, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Microbiological Criteria of Foods - Don Splittsoesser Lecture, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Series II. Talks and Conferences
  - New York State Association of Milk and Food Sanitarians - Talk on Yeast and Molds, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Fungi Conference - South Bend, Indiana, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Southern University Career Forum, 1987-1990 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Pediococcus Talks at U. M. and Cornell (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Symposium on Nurtitional Quality of Food Crops, January 1973 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Series III. Research and Professional
  - The Genesee Brewing Co. and Paper on Brewing Yeast (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Vitamin Assay Methods, 1961-1973 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Research (1), 1972-1978 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Research (2), 1972-1978 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Thiamine Assay (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Proposal for Pediococcus Project, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Pediococcus Hatch Project, 1984-1989 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Pediococcus Project Proposal, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Tim's Report Re: Pediococcus Project (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Pediococcus Progress Reports, 1986-1989 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Other Files from Pediococcus Project (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Pediococcus Project Correspondence, 1986-1988 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Dairy Research Foundation Proposal Application, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Biotechnology Institute, 1984-1988 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Field of Food Science and Technology Graduate Studies Files, 1983-1993 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Field of Food Science and Technology Graduate Student Files and Grades, 1971-1982 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Field of Food Science and Technology Graduate Student Field Reports, 1986-1990 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Files on Shaker Mostafa El-Gendy - Assiut University, Egypt (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Files on Khalel Muhsen Mahdi - Ministry of Health, Baghdad (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Actinomycetes Cellulase Enzymes, Dr. Dexter Bellamy (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Folacin Measurement in Frozen Foods (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Folacin Availability Hatch Project (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Extension Work/Consultin, 1986-1990 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Score Cards - Fermented Milks and Cheeses (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Files on Booker T. Wheatley, 1978-1982 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Visiting Professors and Fellows, 1986-1989 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Harris Graduate Fellowships, 1988-1990 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Sabbatic Leave, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - International Food Science Projects, 1986-1989 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Trip to Antigua, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - International Agriculture Program - Trip to Somalia, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Food Science at Somali National University, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - International Agriculture Program and Food Science, 1986-1989 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - International Agriculture Program and CALS Africa Committee, 1987-1989 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Cornell/Taiwan Cooperative Food Science Program (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Syracuse University Research Corporation (SURC), 1974 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Microbe and Breadmaking Slides (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Proposal Writing, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Series IV. Publications
  - Correspondence and Papers Regarding Field of Food Science, 1978-1988 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - "Nutrient Losses and Malnutrition Due to Food Toxins," Donald Graham (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Papers on Protein Production in Fungi, Donald Graham, 1971; 1976 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - "Factors Affecting Production of Amino Acids by Molds in Synthetic Media," Donald Graham (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Articles and Papers on Fermentation - Various Authors, 1966-1977 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Articles and Papers on Fermented Milk-Wheat - Various Authors, 1954-1975 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Articles and Papers on Fish and Related Topics - Various Authors, 1965-1973 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Papers and Articles on Vitamin A - Various Authors, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Papers on Idli - Various Authors, 1964-1967 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Articles on Iron Bio-availability - Various Authors, 1961-1973 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Articles and Papers on Milk and Dairy - Various Authors, 1969-1974 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Articles and Papers on Nutrition and Food Needs - Various Authors, 1962-1975 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Dairy Methods, Barbano (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Papers on Bacteria in Foods - Various Authors, 1981-1983 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Pediococcus Papers - Various Authors, 1960-1988 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Articles and Papers on Mushroom Culture - Various Authors (1) (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Articles and Papers on Mushroom Culture - Various Authors (2) (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Paper on Modification of Fungi for Food Use, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Series V. Committees
  - CALS Faculty Committee on Admissions, 1981-1991 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Affirmative Action Advisory Board, 1977-1986 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Food Science Advisory Council - Scholarship Committee, 1988-1990 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Food Science Advisory Council - Scholarship Committee, 1991-1993 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Seminar Committee, Spring 1987 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Registration Materials - Food Science, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - CALS Minority Affairs, 1976-1985 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Faculty Council of Representatives, 1980-1984 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Financial Aid Policy Committee, 1977-1983 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Handicapped Committee Program, 1977-1979 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Health Careers Advising, 1983-1993 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Minority Education Committees, 1978-1987 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Minority Faculty/Staff Forum, 1980-1986 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Salaries, Faculty and Staff, 1979-1990 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Search Committee - Food Science and Technology, Geneva, 1983-1985 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence with O. Onayemi, University of IFE, Nigeria, Re: Sabbatical, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - CALS Minority Resource Development Committee, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - CALS Minority Resource Development Committee, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - CALS Minority Resource Development Committee, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - CALS Minority Resource Development Committee, 1991-1994 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Series VI. Organizations
  - National Science Foundation - Minority Research Initiation, 1981-1983 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - National Society of Non-Traditional Agriculturalists, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - National Urban League - Tri-State Minority Faculty Conference, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - "Problems of Negro Families in Tompkins County," A Preliminary Report, 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Equal Opportunity Committee - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges (NASULGC), 1979-1981 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Equal Opportunity Committee - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges (NASULGC), 1980-1983 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Africana Mentorship Program, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Cornell Black Faculty Association, 1985-1987 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Sigma Xi and Pi Kappa Phi Honor Societies (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Education Committee - Cornell Federal Credit Union, 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Education Committee - Cornell Federal Credit Union, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Ithaca-Cayuga Rotary Club (1) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Ithaca-Cayuga Rotary Club (2) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Cornell Faculty Against Apartheid (and Documents Re: Divestment), 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Human Services Coalition, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Black Issues in Higher Education, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Agricultural Missions, Inc., 1985-1989 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Alpha Phi Alpha Fraternity, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - American Indian Affairs and Program at Cornell, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - International Agriculture and Rural Development Board; Board for International Food and Agricultural Development, 1977-1984 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Cornell Black Agriculturalists(Includes Slides and Stamp), 1975-1982 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Black Agriculturalist Career Day, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Commission on Lay Ministry, Episcopal Church, 1987-1990 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - CURW Board, 1982-1985 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Center for Religion, Ethics, and Social Policy (CRESP) (1), 1981-1992 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Center for Religion, Ethics, and Social Policy (CRESP) (2), 1981-1992 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Series VII. Correspondence
  - Correspondence, 1977-1979 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1979-1984 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence with Christiana Ebisi at the African Foods Center, New York, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Dean D. L. Call Correspondence, 1978-1981 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Dean W. K. Kennedy Correspondence, 1976-1981 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence with J. Rober Cooke, Director, Office of Instruction, 1977-1981 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence with Lillian P. Cummings, Kentucky State University, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence with Bill Graves, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Series VIII. Biographical
  - Resumes (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Photographs (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Personal Correspondence, and Memos, 1973-1989 (Box 5, Folder 31)